## Florin LIPAN

## About

I'm a Ruby developer with a strong devops background, leadership experience and a passion for building products. I know my way around AWS, Ansible, Kubernetes, Docker and Linux. I can speak SQL to your database and GraphOL to your clients. I have a personal interest in languages like Crystal and Rust. I know a thing or two about HTML, CSS, Javascript and what makes a good UI/UX. I value clean, simple, boring code and try to be pragmatic while keeping my standards high. I can write concise, well structured documentation. I enjoy learning, teaching and being self-organized.

## Personal

**Email** florinlipan@gmail.com

GitHub / Projects https://github.com/lipanski

Website / Blog https://lipanski.com Place of residence Berlin, Germany

Languages Solid English, German, Romanian. Some French.

## Experience

Chatterbug / Staff Engineer Nov. 2021 - Present

May 2020 - Oct. 2021 Chatterbug / Senior Software Developer

A hands-on experience building a complex language learning and video streaming platform together with the founders of GitHub. I improved the website performance on numerous occasions, nurtured the Rails monolith and designed advanced GraphOL APIs. I helped other developers in their daily work through pairing, code reviews. planning and patience. I introduced Turbo Streams, Stimulus and GraphQL Subscriptions to the stack, significantly reducing our development time. I learned a lot about developing a successful product with a very small team and lean processes.

Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2020 Blacklane / Head of Engineering (Platform)

A partially hands-on management role. I'm providing high-level technical guidance to the Blacklane Platform teams (Infrastructure, Geolocation, Payment, Back-office, Salesforce, Internal APIs, ~15 engineers), trying to empower developers whenever I can, but getting my hands dirty when I'm needed. I'm handling recruiting and interviews, providing feedback in 1:1 sessions and mentoring team members. I'm trying to keep engineering standards high, apps running smoothly and people

engaged and happy.

Blacklane / Lead Backend Developer (Ruby) Sep. 2014 - Jun. 2018

> A merry mix of backend development, devops, software architecture and management tasks. I helped tame the Rails monolith, designed and partially developed the new Booking API and developed various (micro)services in Sinatra or Rack using MySOL, Postgres, Redis, Sidekig, Puma and others. I got deeper into ops, got familiar with a wide range of AWS services from VPCs to CloudFormation and built our infrastructure around Ansible. Over the course of the last year, we shifted towards Kubernetes and Docker. I introduced new processes, handled technical interviews and performed product management tasks. I improved the performance of

our systems and lived to see some beefy infrastructure migration Sundays.

Feb. 2014 - Aug. 2014 Blacklane / Backend Developer (Ruby)

Nov. 2012 - Jan. 2014 Axonic / Full Stack Developer (Ruby on Rails)

> I developed a fairly complex product from scratch, while being the only developer on the project. Working closely with the CEO, I learned not just full stack Ruby on Rails but also what's important to customers, how to plan and how to build a product.

Axonic / Full Stack Developer (PHP5, Symfony) Dec. 2010 - Aug. 2012

Apr. 2009 - Jul. 2010 Pi Technologies / Developer (PHP, CMS, Javascript)

Education

2010 - 2011 Karlsruhe Institute of Technology M. Sc. Informatics (discontinued)

2006 - 2010 Technical University of Cluj-Napoca B. Sc. Informatics, 240 ECTS Points, 9.5/10